Hello everyone welcome back to this another new tutorial topic today we can define and discuss
and going to explore the digital statement in the SQL which allows us to remove records from
a table. So first of all we can define the SQL, digital statement okay. So in this digital statement
in the SQL used to remove records from the table and operation in the managing database okay.
So first of all here I can delete with the single record okay. So now just remove all the
employees name for the employees table. So first of all here I can type this is a
delete for the
employees. So here you can see the employees table and next step here I can just use the
file clause for first name. So define for here the first name suppose is equal to so here I can
just select for the first name suppose like Johan and also here I can use the end operator
and now here define this the last name. So last name is equal to Johan okay. So this is perfect
and the semicolon and here I can use the digital statement to remove the record, Johan from
the employee table. So now just select all and the next cube. Now you can see here this is
row is perfectly affected now okay. So this employee
for delete the specified column. So now just open for another query and now here use the select
mister form the employee stable and create the semicolon and select all then execute. Now you
can see here I can insert for here use the Johan and here you can see perfectly defined okay.
So this is completely used the first column and the last column okay.
So next step here I can create the delete for the multiple records okay.
So the delete statement can also be used to remove multiple records in the single query.
So now just go for here and create simply. So just create the delete from the
D LED from the employee stable and use the order. So now just check for the where is the department.
So define for it is called the department is equal to so now just check for this table
and here I can delete for this HR department okay. So now just define this HR.
So you can see removing for the employees
here work in the HR department for the employee stable okay.
So first of all select and execute now you can see here perfectly two way is completely affected.
So now just verify first of all create in the statement and select and execute now you can see
here perfectly delete for the HR department and the marketing finance and the development okay.
So I hope you perfectly understand the delete statement and how to remove it okay.
So next step perfectly understand delete all the record.
You can delete all the records from a table from the specific information okay. So you can go here
and remove for the employee statement okay.
And just select for the delete from the simply just type the employee stable okay.
So perfectly delete all the records from the employee stable. So first of all I can select
all and execute now you can see here perfectly three row completely affected okay.
So now just go for here and select just verify the statement and you can see only statement
for the total five column and not statement for the row. So this query only move for the
all row from the table effectively okay. So here this is completely done and there we have it
the whole view of the delete statement of the SQL with the three practical example okay.
So I hope you find this tutorial helpful so stay tuned for more SQL tutorial tips and tips
and thank you for watching and happy coding okay.